Matthew Bell

La Mesa, CA 91942

Phone: 858-922-5440 | Email: matthewbell1030@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-bell-developer-artist/ | Github: https://github.com/Mbell42 | Portfolio:

https://matthewgbell-portfolio.com/ | IMDB: https://www.imdb.com/name/nm7347199/?ref =ttfc fc cr226

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in 3D Animation and VFX. 4 years of experience in film and mobile video game production. Proficient in Agile software development, and able to learn new skills quickly. Collaborates well with any size team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- UI / UX Design
- Procedural Design & Documentation
- Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, MySQL
- Experience with version control systems, responsive design, working with command lines, debugging, and designing and implementing front-end systems.
- Applications: JIRA, Visual Studio Code, Git, Microsoft Office, Adobe Suite, Autodesk Maya/Motionbuilder, Pixologic Zbrush, The Foundry NukeX

PROJECTS

Steadfast | https://github.com/Mbell42/steadfast | https://mysterious-castle-55265.herokuapp.com/

- Steadfast enables companies to easily find contacts at prospective companies and integrate contacts through our seamless experience CMS
- Collaborated with a 4-person team for 3 weeks
- Authentication/Authorization Components and Logic, Testing, Logo
- MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, React, BcryptJS

Employee-directory | https://github.com/Mbell42/19 react employee-directory | https://react-employee-directory-hw-19.herokuapp.com/

- Mock employee-directory that will support searching by categories and employee names. Will populate with 20 random employees upon load and each reset
- Created front-end elements to
- Solo project
- MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS

Weather Dashboard | https://github.com/Mbell42/06_weather-dashboard

- Weather app using API requests that will dynamically update HTML elements based on user search
- Solo project
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Agricultural Robotics Assembler

November 2020 - April 2021

Vision Robotics Corporation

San Diego, CA

- Performed electrical and mechanical assembly/disassembly of agricultural robots and subassemblies from blueprints and written instructions with minimal direction and supervision.
- Soldered and repaired SMT and Though-Hole circuit boards.
- Tested new designs under varying conditions.

Key Accomplishments

- Achieved basic soldering competency.
- Sole operator in the workshop with limited instruction or supervision.

Quality Control Specialist II

August 2016 - June 2019

MACHINE Studios LLC.

San Diego, CA

Developed and executed successful test plans, procedures, use cases, and provided indepth analysis to the Design and Programming Teams. While at MACHINE Studios LLC., I worked with the CEO and departments to aid in the company's adoption of AGILE workflows by helping to write process and communication documentation. This benefitted the company by reducing the amount of time used in daily meetings by over 25% and reduced the amount of overtime during each sprint by up to 10 hours.

Key Accomplishments:

- Owner of the daily build and distribution process for internal teams, and a key part of the distribution process to clients and external development partners.
- Worked with Design Director and CEO to create new communication and process documentation for the adoption of AGILE workflows.
- Worked with Design Director and CEO to create a Bug Tracking System for use with product development.
- Improved company products' usability through feature enhancement requests based on testing and user experience, as well as performing competitive analysis on existing products.

Stereo Compositor

August 2014 - June 2015

LEGEND 3D

San Diego, CA

 Provided compositing solutions for complex and new challenges with a small team, pushing the boundaries of RealD 3D technology, as well as creating rotoscopes and clean-plates for shots for 4 movies.

Key Accomplishments:

- Provided Stereo Compositing for the world's first 360 degree VR in RealD 3D; "Art of Patron"
- Provided hand-drawn solutions to replace footage for 2 complex shots in <u>The Divergent</u>
 Series: Insurgent (2015)
- Provided Stereo Compositing for <u>The Walk</u>, <u>Ant-Man</u>, and <u>Poltergeist</u> (2015)

Teacher Assistant

June 2015 - August 2015

Platt College

San Diego, CA

• Assisted teacher with lectures and grading tests, and students with homework and class projects. Helped students to realize their potential, by elucidating complex concepts and helping to set achievable goals.

Key Accomplishments:

- Consolidated skills I had learned in class through teaching.
- Learned to communicate complex topics.
- Inspired others to reach their goals.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate:

UCSD, San Diego, CA - 2020

Bachelor of Science, Media Arts Degree:

Platt College, San Diego, CA – **2014**

Associates in Applied Science, Graphic Design Degree:

Platt College, San Diego, CA - 2013